KYLE MORRISON | curriculum vitae

My interests and technical expertise include design and development of virtual reality experiences, game design and development, empathy in virtual environments, web development, programming languages, digital media production, entertainment, and software engineering. Address: 105 West Blvd N Columbia, MO 65203

Phone: 573.291.8716

Email: kyle.morrison25@uga.edu

Web: kylecmorrison.com

EDUCATION

Master of Fine Arts | Dramatic Media Production

University of Georgia Graduation Date: May 2018 Current GPA: 3.95

Bachelor of Science | Information Technology

University of Missouri Graduation Date: May 2015 GPA in Major: 3.258

HONORS

University of Missouri Deans List 2014 – 2015 University of DeVry Deans List 2009 – 2011 Projects presented at FutureX Live 2016 Best Game Athens Game Jam 2017 2nd Place UPE CS & IT Showcase 2015 3rd Place and Best Design Hack GSU 2017 Runner Up HoloHack 2016 Atlanta 3rd Place UGA Hacks 2016

SKILLS

C, C++, C#, Perl, Java, MEL, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, PHP, and HTML 3D modeling, animation, and rigging with Maya Virtual experiences and game development with Unity and Unreal Engine Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office Suite, iLife, and iWorks products

EXPERIENCE

3D Modeler and Programmer, Games and Virtual Environments Lab University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia

August 2016 – Present

- Programmed VR experiments in C# and Unity
- Developed immersive 3D virtual environments and original software for researching influence factors, decision making, and perception

Software Engineer Intern, Rockwell Collins

Portland, Oregon

- Used AR and VR technologies to develop an <u>immersive 3D virtual</u> <u>cockpit environment</u> for pilots flying in a Flight Deck Simulator
- Modeled in Blender and programmed in C#, C++, and Unity

May 2017 – August 2017

Graduate Research Assistant, Ideas for Creative Exploration (ICE) August 2015 - May 2017 University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia Created collaborative works across multiple disciplines Facilitated collaborative projects and proposals with faculty, students, and community members Peer Learning Assistant, Introduction to Entertainment Media August 2014 – May 2015 University of Missouri College of Engineering, Columbia, Missouri Provided support for students completing projects in Adobe Photoshop and Acid Pro Graded all projects and test material submitted by thirty students **Audio Engineer**, Voice of Literacy January 2014 – May 2015 University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri Performed as audio technician during interviews by maintaining audio and interference levels while recording audio with audacity Edited and distributed interviews for online publication by cutting audio and removing unwanted noise **Technical Support**, The Reflector April 2013 – May 2015 University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri Provided technology support for all students and faculty Checked-out, checked-in, and serviced technology equipment and resource material Demonstrated creative software such as Adobe Creative Suite and iLife to five classes with an average of thirty students Web and Graphic Designer, Luebbering Photography February 2010 – Present Holts Summit, Missouri Designed all aspects of the Luebbering Photography image such as the logo, business cards, magnets, and promotional material Managed Luebbering Photography's website and the design Edited photos to remove blemishes and add visual effects Geek Squad Agent, Best Buy Geek Squad February 2010 - July 2010 Jefferson City, Missouri Assisted customers with service and repair issues Performed computer installations and technical support **PROJECTS** Vaccine World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment September 2017 Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to teach participants about the flu vaccine Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Paint World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment November 2017 Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to research branding effects on objects Modeled and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Oreo World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment November 2017 Programmer and Designer

Experiment designed to research branding effects on object

Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya

Designed and programmed game using C# and Unity

Bike World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment October 2017 Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to research virtual worlds distraction from pain Designed and programmed game using C# and Unity Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Fruit Punch! | Desktop/Mobile AR Card Game April 2017 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Vuforia SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Implemented image recognition, player health, and card augmentation using C# slimGYM VR | Desktop VR Game April 2017 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed workout simulator game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Implemented voice controls, workout training, and NPC AI using C# Swamp Hatch | Desktop VR Game January 2017 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed frog adventure game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Implemented locomotion system and NPC AI using C# Stickygrams | Mobile AR Application December 2016 Programmer and Designer Augmented Reality application for HoloLens that allows users to leave holographic messages to their friends and the public Designed front-end user experience using C# and Unity. Placed as a runner up in Holohack 2016 in Atlanta, GA World Tour Z | Desktop VR Game November 2016 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed procedurally generated workout game using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Implemented bike and running locomotion system using C# Won 3rd Place at University of Georgia Hackathon Mirror World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment September 2016 Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to research narcissism Textured and corrected meshes on assets in Autodesk Maya Designed and implemented character using Fuse and Unity Featured project at FutureX Live 2016 Starboard | Desktop VR Game September 2016 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed open world exploration game using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya

Implemented navigation system using the Vive SDK and C#

Featured project at FutureX Live 2016

Public Speaking Simulator | Desktop VR Experience May 2016 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya Programmed multiplayer networking architecture Implemented hand tracking using the Leap Motion SDK Implemented live feedback from virtual viewers VR Maze Racing | Android VR Game April 2016 Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed a maze based strategy game using C#, Unity, and the Cardboard SDK Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya <u>"in image of" | Video Installation</u> February 2016 Videographer, Animator, and Editor Rotoscoped and animated scenes using Adobe Photoshop Filmed and directed choreographed dance scenes Edited footage using Adobe After Effects and Premiere Created a Max MSP patch to control video installation December 2015 Black Lives Matter Project | Website Web Developer Designed website for an undergraduate's Black Lives Matter data visualization thesis project Programmed site using HTML, CSS, and JSON UniVirt | Desktop VR Experience May 2015 Designer, Programmer, and Team Lead Led small team in creating a virtual tour of a section of campus at MU Modeled and textured buildings and objects using Autodesk Maya Designed and programmed game using blueprints, Unreal Engine, and Oculus SDK **VR to IRL | Windows Program** February 2015 **Designer and Programmer** Created an application that allowed the user to switch between a windowed Oculus application and a webcam attached to the front of an HMD with gestures provided by the Leap Motion SDK Designed a VR workstation to be easily transported on the user's back <u>Luebbering Photography | Business Design</u> April 2011 Graphic and Web Designer Designed all aspects of the Luebbering Photography image such as the logo, business cards, magnets, and promotional material Managed Luebbering Photography's website and the design Edited photos to remove blemishes and add visual effects **Professional Development** President | Society for Students in Animation, UGA Chapter 2016 - Present 2015 - Present ■ Member | Georgia Game Developers Association, Athens Chapter ■ **Member** | Association for Computing Machinery, UGA Chapter 2015 - Present President | Idea Lab, UGA Interdisciplinary Student Organization 2016 - 2017■ **Member** | Tau Sigma Honor Society, MU Chapter 2012 - 2015